[Music]
Insurance can be one of those expense
that might skip our mind when we look at
making a purchase and decide on the
upkeeping and the maintenance cost even
reviews might skip them but as a owner
you really can't
I brought home my BMW g310r in March
2022 where the motorcycle arrived at the
dealership in the last week of Feb and
went for registration and insurance
abiding the law the third party
insurance was done for five years till
2027 while the owner's damage policy was
done for one year in the past I have
done videos on insurance and insurance
claim and this time I will be covering
the first year Insurance renewal on my
three 10 hours around 15 days prior to
the due date I Got a notification email
from BMW motorard about the renewal
followed by a call from their insurance
department the first thing which I
always ask is idv the insured declared
value which is actually the sum assured
by the insurance company on your vehicle
the first year usually takes the maximum
hit of around 20 percent of depreciation
on next showroom value the value can be
further customized to reduce but I won't
recommend doing that a lower idv will
bring down your premium amount but it
will also significantly reduce the
amount you will receive in case of
stolen vehicle or total loss incident in
my case I got the Max idv of rupees 2
like 35 000 for my one year old 310 and
the base premium for that came at around
rupees 3308 being a new motorcycle it is
always recommended to get a zero depth
cover for as long as possible zero dip
or Bumper to Bumper Insurance takes
cover on most of the depreciated parts
and Replacements where your insurance
will cover the complete cost of
replacement for most of the parts in
case of accident adding to this BMW
Motorhead was also providing rti in the
same package which stands for return to
invoice this is an interesting scheme
suppose a vehicle got stolen or reported
as total loss in an accident which is
beyond repair usually in such cases the
insurance companies pay the idv amount
or the maximum percentage of the idv
amount to the owner in this case if a
brand new g310r costs around 3 lakh
seventy thousand on road then after a
mishap the insurance company will only
get you the idv amount which in my case
will be just 2 lakh 35 000 and sadly
that won't get me a brand new G3 10r to
cover this difference we have RTI that
is written to invoice where the
insurance company will pay you the
complete invoice amount on the new
motorcycle of the same make and model
the Highlight here is that the insurance
company will pay for the complete
registration and taxes on the on-road
price of the new vehicle which is a big
relief accessories might not be covered
in this as it depends upon policy to
policy
in my case I paid an additional of 2468
rupees for both zero dip and return to
invoice which seems reasonable for the
coverage as far as I know BMW motor at
India has partnered with Bajaj Allianz
and ICICI Lombard for the insurance so
you might get your policy from any one
of them however it is always better to
check it with your authorized service
center on which companies providing the
better service and assistance in terms
of claim settlement in that particular
region I was provided with the ICICI
Lombard Insurance where the insurance
premium with zero dip and RTI stood at
around
5776 on which I got a 20 no claims bonus
for not claiming the insurance in the
first year the no claims bonus of 662
rupees brought down the premium to 5114
rupees upon which the GST was added
which brought the final total to 6036
rupees and that is how much I paid for
my first year renewal which also adds to
the ownership experience so let me know
if you want more such ownership
experience videos in future so that's it
for this video and I hope you guys have
liked it
[Music]